-麦克斯  -不
- Max. - No,
少来我面前摆出那"我是老板
don't come over here with that "I'm the boss,
你是服务员"的姿态
you are the waitress" look,
因为老娘也可以立刻回敬你
'cause I could just as easily give you
"我是杀手  你是待宰羔羊"的姿态
the "I'm the murderer, you're the victim" look.
第2桌的金刚芭比
The muscular woman at table two
退了她的贝果
is sending her bagel back.
她说她点了原味儿
She said she ordered a plain one.
抱歉  你说她点的是杂粮口味吗
I'm sorry, did you say she wanted a multi-grain?
是原味儿
No, plain.
全麦口味吗
Whole grain?
是原味儿
No, plain.
-大蒜口味  -不是
- Garlic? - No.
就原味儿  原味儿啊
The plain! The plain!
虽然等了两年
It took me two years,
但终于让他说出口了[捉弄阿憨口音]
but I finally got him to say it.
别告诉我你没听到那猫叫声
Are you telling me you don't hear that cat?
我们得放它进来
We have to let it in.
明显是只流浪喵星人
It's clearly a stray,
或是我上周在捐血车附近碰到的海军男
or this marine I met last week at a blood drive.
上周有个男的在门外大喊
Last week there was a man outside our door screaming,
"我被人捅了"
"I've been stabbed,"
而你只是回敬他一句"闭嘴"
and all you did was yell, "shut up."
因为他说他"好像"被人捅了
Because he said, "I think I've been stabbed""
要么是被捅  要么是没被捅  朋友
You're either stabbed, or you're not stabbed, my friend.
你听  那个喵星人像是在说"哈喽[你好]"
Listen, it sounds like the cat's saying hello.
哈喽  哈喽
Hello, hello.
你听  它在说话呢
Listen, it's talking.
它在说"帮帮我  让我进来"
It's saying, "Help. Can I come in"
是吗
Really?
我觉得它是在说
'cause I think it's saying,
"我没事  你们回去睡吧"
"I'm fine. Go back to sleep."
你听  这句明显是在说
Come on, it clearly just said,
"让我进来  别理金发妞
"Let me in. Ignore the blonde.
她是个贱人"
She's a bitch"
你不能有人来我们家门口
Look, you can't just let in everything
说声"哈喽"  就让他进来吧
that shows up at our door and says hello.
为啥不行  姐就这么干过
Yeah, I can. I've done it.
不行  麦克斯
Max, we can't.
我们不能变成猫痴女
We can't become cat ladies.
这一开始都是发善心
And it always starts out innocently,
救一只小野猫
rescuing a stray,
但之后就得再弄一只
but then you have to get another one
去上班时它们才有个伴
so that they can entertain each other while you're at work.
接着不知不觉  就多混了四只进来
And then somewhere along the line, four more sneak in,
你会想  "没事啦  没问题的
and you think, "We're good. We're cool.
我们是有六只猫的姐妹花"
We're the cute girls with six cats."
之后某天就是你上了《动物警察》节目
And then, one day, there you are on Animal Cops,
哭喊"别带走我的小天使
screaming, "Don't take my babies!
这27只小天使是我的一切"
These 27 angels is all I got!"
事情就会是这样  麦克斯
That's how it goes, Max.
一旦收留了第1只  最后就会变成27只
Once you get one, you get 27.
-才不是呢  -是吗
- Not true. - Really?
那你床下收了多少只花园矮人[庭园摆饰]
How many garden gnomes do you have under your bed?
27只
27.
干嘛
What?
他们理解这只是暂时的  在等我有院子的那天
They understand I'm only keeping them there
就把他们放出来了啊
until I get a yard.
拜托嘛  我想要一只小喵喵
Come on. I want a kitty.
麦麦的小喵喵  麦麦的小喵喵
Kitty for Max. Kitty for Max.
麦克斯  我们已经有匹马了
Max, we already have a horse.
我们养不起新宠物了
We can't afford another animal.
-咱们没钱  -拜托嘛
- We're broke. - Come on.
栗宝需要一个朋友
Chestnut needs a friend.
他超想跟别人吐槽我们
He is dying to trash us to someone,
但对象只有那只
and all he's got is that rat
只管自家事的老鼠
who is super self-involved.
是哪个王八蛋啊  都这么晚了
Who the hell is that?  It's so late.
可能是那喵星人
It's probably the cat,
也可能是布鲁克林连环强奸犯
or the guy who's raping girls in Brooklyn.
开门看运气吧
Open the door, and roll the dice.
拜托
Oh, please.
拜托告诉我
Please, somebody tell me
有人已经宰了那只贱猫
they killed that damn cat.
还有  那只猫去哪里学说"哈喽"的啊
And where did it learn how to say hello?
我就说吧
Told you.
被它害得我整晚不能睡
It's been keeping me up all night.
这可怜的喵星人在我们门外
This poor cat has been crying at our door
叫了好几晚想进来
every night trying to get in,
想蹭两口温牛奶
trying to get a little warm milk,
可能再加两口鲔鱼
maybe a skosh of tuna.
麦克斯  那是我们明天的晚餐
Max, that's our dinner tomorrow.
等等  你们要小心
Wait. Be careful.
猫不见得一定是猫
A cat is not always a cat.
请继续往下说
Oh, please continue.
在波兰  我们相信如果你横死野外
In Poland, we believe if you die outside,
你会转生为一只猫
you're reincarnated as a cat.
我是唯一觉得波兰
Am I the only one who thinks Poland
像出奇人异事秀的地方吗
sounds like a real freak show?
绝对别让猫进来
So never let a cat in,
因为那只是某个转生的人
because it's just a person that's been reincarnated
会带各种"坏犹太"进来
and will bring in all the bad jews？
你是想说坏运气吧
I think you mean juju.
是吗
Oh, do I?
晚安啦
Nighty-night.
我们只需要忍它一会
Look, we just have to put up with it,
等上一阵  它就会自己走掉了
and after a while, it'll go away on its own.
自己走掉
Go away on its own?
它是流浪喵星人  不是我老爸
It's a stray cat, not my father.
晚安  麦克斯
Good night, Max.
行  麦麦没小喵喵
Fine. No kitty for Max.
麦麦没小喵喵
No kitty for Max.
麦克斯  你看  我就说它会消停吧
See, Max, I told you the cat would stop.
麦克斯
Max?
Max.
妈  我们能养它吗  能养吗
Can we keep it, mom? Can we keep it?
厄尔  你不会想要一只喵星人吧
Earl, you don't want a cat, do you?
喵星人  我死都不要
A cat? God, no.
喵星人会偷你的大麻
Cats steal your weed.
卡洛琳  你看
See, Caroline?
没人想要喵星人
Nobody wants the cat.
我们来收留它
We're keeping it,
我觉得现在可以开始办庆喵宴了
and I think we should start celebrating right meow.
麦克斯  你都没试着说服他
Max, you didn't even try to convince him.
拜托  厄尔
Come on, Earl.
你不想要只猫吗
Don't you want a cat?
厄尔来只小喵喵  厄尔来只小喵喵
Kitty for Earl. Kitty for Earl.
我老得不能养猫了
I'm too old to have a cat.
我估计再过个半年
I'm about six months away
我就得拉屎在"人"砂盆里了
from crapping in a box myself.
奥列格  你对猫有何感觉
Oleg, how do you feel about cats?
爱死了  去百老汇看过九次
Loved it. Saw it nine times on Broadway.
很有才的音乐剧
Very clever show,
但有点贵
but a little expensive.
这辈子花最多钱看的猫[下阴]跳舞
The most I've ever paid to see a pussy dance.
目前还是我们收留喵星人
So far we're keeping the cat.
阿憨  你想要只猫吗
Hey, Han, do you want a cat?
你终于能有个跟你一个大小的朋友了
You could finally have a friend your own size.
来嘛  你能骑它来上班呢
Come on, you could ride it to work.
不  我不能养猫
No, I can't have a cat.
它们懒惰  脾气坏  又爱鄙视人
They're lazy, moody, and judgmental.
简直就是你的翻版
I don't need another you.
-而且它们又不会表达爱意  -当然会啊
- Plus, they don't show affection. - Sure they do.
你知道怎么让它们展露就行了
You just have to know how to get it out of them.
喵星人喜欢被人轻轻打屁股
Cats love to be lightly spanked on their bottom.
我无法理解猫为什么会喜欢那样
I don't understand why a cat would like that.
太难懂了
It's so mysterious.
喵喵  喵喵  喵喵喵喵喵喵
Kitty. Kitty. Kitty-kitty-kitty.
阿喵  阿喵  阿喵阿喵阿喵
我还是不能养猫
Well, I can't have a cat.
我整天得上班
I work all the time.
我为什么会喜欢刚才那种感觉
Why did I like that so much?
不知道
I don't know.
因为被有咪咪的人碰了吗
Something with boobs was touching you.
也有别的有咪咪的人碰我啊
People with boobs touch me.
她指除了你妈以外的人
She means aside from your mom.
那就没了
Then, no.
我们问过所有认识的了
Well, we've asked everyone we know,
问完我好伤感  因为这些人
and now I'm depressed, because this
就是我们所有认识的人
is everyone we know.
开始问餐厅里的人吧
Let's start asking people in the diner.
我们得为它找个家
We need to find it a place to live.
为什么
Why?
为什么它不能住在我怀里
Why can't it live right here in my arm
睡在我天然火辣胸器之间
in between my hot and naturals?
喵喵  喵喵  喵喵喵喵喵喵
Kitty. Kitty. Kitty-kitty-kitty.
我得承认  感觉是挺爽的
I have to admit, that does feel kind of good.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
我听到了你们在问人
I overheard you two asking people
有没兴趣收留猫
if they want a cat,
我真的很想要一只
And I'd really love one.
真的吗  我们正好有一只
Really? Well, we have your cat.
等等  等等  别着急
Whoa. Whoa. Not so fast.
我得先问几个问题
I got a couple of questions first.
你抽烟吗
Do you smoke?
抽
Yes.
你喝酒吗
Drink?
喝
Yes.
处方药呢
Prescription drugs.
偶尔
Occasionally.
别管喵星人了
Forget the cat.
带我回家吧
Will you take me home?
喵喵  你会喜欢这小姐的
Kitty, you're gonna love this lady.
她抽烟  喝酒  又嗑处方药
She smokes, drinks, does prescription drugs,
明显是强效止痛药上瘾
Which we all know means Oxy.
你们好啊
Hi.
天啊  她来了
Oh, my God. These she is.
她真是太"它喵"可爱了
She's purr-fect.
进来吧  欢迎回家
Come in. Welcome home, you.
你看  麦克斯  太好了
See, Max? It's great.
这里是什么情况啊
What the hell is going on in here?
你看这堆猫
Look at all these cats
塞在这小房子里
crammed in this little space.
也太惨了
It's so sad.
现在就只差萨拉·麦克拉克伦
The only thing missing is Sarah Mclachlan
在角落唱歌了
singing in the corner.
还好吧
What? It's fine.
也没这么多
There's not that many.
喵星人袭击啊
They're attacking!
抱歉  他喜欢金发妞
Sorry. He loves blondes.
还喜欢拉屎在地毯上呢
And apparently pooping on the carpet.
不行  闪闪  不可以
No, twinkles, no.
好吧  我来简单介绍一下
Oh, okay, quick introductions.
这些是  贝贝  福福  窖窖
That's Bethany, Radford, Cellars,
林林  诺诺
Franklin, Eleanor,
丁丁  髭髭  兹兹  梅梅
Pudding, Mustachio, Mitzi, Meredith,
特特  尼尼
Baxter, Bernie.
她居然记得他们全部的名字
She remembers all of their names?
我连破我处的男人
I don't even remember the name of the guy
名字都不记得
I lost my virginity to.
我最多就记得是某某教练
Best I can do is "coach" something.
凯瑟琳  我觉得这很有爱
Well, Catherine, I think it's lovely
你有个一个庞大又多毛的家庭
That you have such a big, loving hairy family,
跟卡戴珊家族一样
kind of like the Kardashians.
只有24只而已啦
There's only 24.
变成31只了
31.
在这些狂猫病疯猫咬我们
Let's go before one of these rabid cats bites us
把我们变成流浪街头却从来不冷的
and we become half-human, half-cat hybrids
半人半猫混合体前  开溜吧
who wander the streets but are never cold.
我们得去走廊上讨论一下
We're just gonna go have a little conversation in the hall.
顺便一说  那只母猫
And F.Y.I., the mother looks
好像在吃小猫呢
like she's eating the little one.
我就随便说说
Just a thought.
但我说的原因是因为那小猫在她嘴里
I'm only saying that 'cause it's in her mouth.
兹兹  松口
Mitzi, release!
走吧
Let's go!
在刚才的五分钟里
In less than five minutes,
就从24只变成了31只
It went from 24 to 31,
我还看到两只喵星人在角落
and I saw two cats in the corner
用"狗"爬式做爱呢
doing it doggie style,
再过两个月  估计就能突破50只喵星人了
So in two months, we could be looking at 50 cats.
麦克斯  用狗爬式不会怀孕啦[会的]
Max, you can't get pregnant doggie style.
对吧
Right?
我们不能进去了
We can't go back in.
里面毛掉得满坑满谷
There's so much hair in there,
我看见一只喵星人在用粘毛刷呢
I saw a cat using a lint roller.
好吧  但如果不把她留在这里
Okay, but if we don't leave her here,
我们就只剩一条路了
We only have one other option.
不行  不许送喵喵去收容所
No, kitty is not going to a shelter.
为什么  很多猫都被人收养
Why? Lots of cats get adopted
然后住进一个漂亮的家
and end up in beautiful homes.
我不想说出口
Look, I didn't want to say this,
但她不够漂亮
but she's not pretty enough.
你在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
她不够漂亮
She's not pretty enough.
别这样  虽然她没有经典的美猫脸
Come on, she doesn't have classic good looks,
但也呆萌呆萌的啊
but she's adorkable.
我们不能送她进动物收容所
We cannot take her to a shelter.
她会死在里面
She'll die there.
而且虽然大家都说想要好脾气的
And, yeah, everyone says they want one with a nice personality,
但真正想要的还是性感热辣"小野猫"
but they really just want a hot, sexy, young kitten
看到球[蛋蛋]在面前还会很兴奋的那种
who still gets excited about balls in her face.
姑娘们  一切还好吗
Everything okay, ladies?
不  一点都不好
No, everything is far from okay.
我的皮靴变雪地靴了
My boots are now UGGs,
真的谢谢你里面漫天飞舞的猫毛
thanks to all the cat hair in there.
不许抓
Ow! Stop it!
抱歉  是娜娜
Sorry, that's Gina.
她有躁郁症  而且还不愿意吃药
She's bipolar, and she refuses to take her meds.
快停手  娜娜
Ow! Ow! Stop it, Gina!
凯瑟琳  对不起了
I'm sorry, Catherine.
这事情看来是不行了
This isn't gonna work out.
其实不是你不好
It's nothing personal.
只是你是个疯子
It's just that you're crazy.
我真的好心碎啊
Truly, I'm heartbroken.
我都替她取好名字了呢
I already have a name picked out for her.
薇薇二号
Veronica two.
停下
Ow! Stop it!
我得先进去了
I got to go!
谁想吃零食
Who wants treat?
我就确认一下
Um, just so we all know,
薇薇一号是自杀的  对吧
Veronica one committed suicide, right?
喵喵  我们会给你找户好人家
Kitty, we're gonna find you a nice home.
想养只喵星人吗
Want a cat?
要免费喵星人吗
Free cat?
想养只喵星人吗
Want a cat?
你一定会爱上这里的
You are going to love it here.
公园坡区就像是布鲁克林的比佛利山庄
Park Slope is like the Beverly Hills of Brooklyn.
貌似来了个有钱人
Here comes a good one.
想养只喵星人吗
Hey. Want a cat.
你刚说什么
Excuse me?
喵星人
Cat?
好  给我来点可卡因
Yeah, I'll take some crack.
她说的是"喵星人"
She said "cat."
我们在为一只猫找一个完美的家
We're looking for a nice home for a cat.
-所以不是可卡因  -不是
- Oh, so no crack. - No.
我干嘛要养一只猫
Well, why would I want a cat?
老子爱的是嗑药好吗
I'm a crackhead.
小喵喵
Well, kitty,
虽然这个决定很艰难
as hard as this is,
我觉得是时候让你
I think it's time to let you
重回这个世界的怀抱了
back out there into the world.
至少我们把你放在一个有钱人的住宅区
At least we leave you in a rich neighborhood;
让你新生活的起点更高
You'll have a better shot at life.
麦克斯  你真的狠得下心吗
Max, you are okay with this?
我当初把我亲戚家的熊孩子
Well, I was more okay
扔在街上时  比现在还狠得下心
when I did this with my cousin's baby.
你自由了
There you go.
对  把她放到隔壁房子
Oh, yeah. Move him to the next house.
朝南向阳  还是战前风格建筑
South-facing sun. Pre-war building.
她肯定会喜欢的
She'll love it.
走吧
There you go.
你现在在公园坡区
You live in Park Slope now.
这里的人喜欢收养一个非洲宝宝
You can adopt an African baby
然后把它放在价值900块的婴儿车里到处晃悠
and wheel it around in a $900 stroller.
你怎么知道这是我的B计划
Can you believe that was my plan "B"?
走  快走开
Run! Run away.
走吧
Go.
算了  她现在就住这里
Ah, screw it. She lives here now.
瞧
Look.
这家人有台钢琴耶
They have a piano.
你可以录玩钢琴的视频
You can make videos.
你肯定会成为网上红猫
You'll be a Youtube star.
再见了  小喵喵
Bye, kitty.
我真惊讶你居然没拦着我
Wow, I'm shocked you didn't stop me.
拦着你
Stop you?
如果我早知道可以这样
If I had known that was option,
我会让你把我扔到那房子里面
I would have had you stuff me in there.
我在想小喵喵现在
I wonder what kitty's doing
在她的豪华别墅里干嘛
in her fancy town house right now.
她可能依偎在一个
She's probably snuggling with
喜欢阅读的老基佬身旁
an older gay guy who likes to read.
因为基佬是现在
You know, 'cause gay guys
世界上唯一还在阅读的族群
are the only ones who still read.
他们俩可能窝在沙发上
They're probably on the couch right now
一起看《加菲猫2  双猫记》
with A Tale of Two Kitties.
我真为我们感到骄傲
I'm proud of us.
我们无私地给予了那只猫
We selflessly gave that cat a better life
我们永远也无法给予的好生活
than we could ever afford for ourselves.
别想跟着沾光
Oh, don't try to get in on that.
是我干了一件好事
I did the right thing.
你差点把她
You tried to leave her
扔在那个疯女人的疯猫窝里
at that crazy lady's pussy riot.
打扰你们了
Hi. Excuse me.
我能不能把这张传单贴在你们窗户旁
Would it be okay if I put this flier next to your window?
-不行  -当然行
- No. - Sure.
我们的猫金科希丢了
We lost our cat, Jinxy, like,
大约一周前  就在这附近丢的
a week ago in this neighborhood.
你们有见过她吗
Have you seen her?
-没有  -当然没有
- No. - No.
我很久没见过猫了
I haven't seen a cat in a long time.
我昨天还跟她念叨
I was just saying to her yesterday,
"我好久没见过猫了"
"I haven't seen a cat in a long time."
你怎么会不在她脖子上弄个项圈呢
Um, how come you didn't have a collar on her?
她连身份标签都没有
And where's her I.D. Tag?
就算是我妈  也会给我弄个身份标签
Even my mother had an I.D. Tag on me.
虽然是灭蚤颈圈  但总比...
Well, it was a flea collar, but...
你为什么过了这么久才来贴传单找猫
Why did it take you so long to put the signs up?
你们是怎么了
Um, what's happening?
事情是这样的
Um, here's what's happening:
我们非常乐意
we are more than happy
把这个寻猫启事贴上
to put up this flier of your cat,
虽然我们从来没见过这只小猫咪
which we have never, ever seen.
说真的  现在猫都跑到哪里去了
I mean, seriously, where did all the cats go?
跑到皇后区吗  还是斯塔顿岛
Queens? Staten Island?
反正它们决不可能在这一带
'cause they're not in this neighborhood.
好吧
Okay.
你们俩好奇怪哦
This was weird.
这只猫是你的那只小喵喵吗
Is there any way this cat isn't kitty?
就是她
Nope, that's her.
一样的绿眼睛  一样的耳朵轮廓
Same green eyes, same notch in the ear.
哈喽  哈喽
Hello. Hello.
天啊  天啊
Oh, God. Oh, God.
姑娘们  干嘛在垂头丧气
Hey, girls. What's shaking?
我就不会  紧身衣把我包得紧实挺拔
Not me, 'cause I'm all held in.
抱歉  苏菲  小蛋糕窗口
Sorry, Sophie, the cupcake window
白天不营业
isn't open during the day.
又不是要你说整段人生经历
I don't need your life story.
老娘就买个小蛋糕而已
I just need a damn cupcake.
苏菲  你还记得那只
Sophie, do you remember that cat
在我们楼外大声哀嚎的喵星人吗
that was crying outside our building?
记得  你把它灭了吗
Yeah, you put it down?
我们以为她是一只流浪猫
We thought it was a stray,
所以我们试图找人收养她
so we tried to find a home for it,
但找不到
but couldn't.
所以你把它灭了
So you put it down.
没有啦
No.
我们把它扔在一个超级好的住宅区
We left it in a really nice neighborhood.
所以找了个有钱人去灭了它吗
Oh, so a rich person put it down?
后来我们发现它根本不是流浪猫
It turns out it wasn't a stray at all.
我们刚见到了它的主人
We just met its owner.
这就是那只猫  苏菲
This is the cat, Sophie.